welcome back
today we are going to enter the LuV tier
to do that
the first thing we have to do is build an assembly line
this is a multi block which is rather complex to use
but let's start by crafting its parts
crafting those components is not easy nor cheap
and even our automatic crafting system has issues with it
the main problem is that
we do not have a crafting unit capable of handling that amount of materials
so we first make some more storage
we should also make some crafting co-processor
to speed up the crafting process
and once we have added some new and more powerful crafting units
we can finally start working on our assembly line parts
this is going to take some time
so we can do some other things
such as farming withers while we wait
we will need those nether stars later on
however after our brief hunting
we find out that
our crafting system hasn't made much progress
and the main issue seems to be that
our processor can't keep up with all the items
it has to move around the various machines
we could increase the amount of co-processors
but the best solution is to reduce the amount of tasks our processor has to do
we can multiply the amount of materials in the patterns
so that
instead of moving 64 times one dust to the furnace
the processor will just move a stack of dusts once
and while at it
we can also equip our furnace with better coils
so that it will cook more stuff at once
after editing the patterns and restarting the crafting job
we can see the difference in the speed
at which items are being moved to the machines
and after not much time
we can see that our crafting processes are idling
the reason is that
we are crafting thousands of SMD components in a small assembler
16 at a time
and each batch also takes quite some time
we have already split the load across different assemblers
but it doesn't make a noticeable difference
even though four assemblers should be four times faster than one
we could use a higher tier assembler
but the power consumption would grow exponentially
so we need a multi block
the first option is the gregtech ++ one
but that requires ZPM stuff that we don't have access to yet
the second option is to parallelize a stack of assemblers inside a processing array
however
that machine doesn't scale well
when we will need to further upgrade it
the third option is using normal mode precision assembler
we crafted last episode
the issue was that the casings of its structure
required an LuV assembler to be crafted
however
if we want it to work in normal mode
we can use the lower tier casings, the imprecise ones
that way the assembler will fully live to its name
after preparing the patterns
we craft just the minimal amount required to form the structure
and to make that thing work fast
we shall have a 16 amps energy hatch
that way
it will work twice as fast as 16 IV assemblers
and you can already see how charging its personal buffer
takes a toll on our main battery
once everything is ready
we assemble the assembler structure
we fill all the non-mandatory casings with cheap buses
and now we can turn that thing on
and see how little it takes now to make hundreds of SMDs
the last bottleneck is our circuit assemblers
so we add a couple more
one for each circuit step
and then we can take a break and AFK a bit
or maybe we could just farm more nether stars
after the quick break
our assembly line is ready
this multi block can be built with different lengths
every additional slice adds space for one more input item
we can also rotate it using a wrench
to build it vertically and have it use less space
and for the moment
we are going to build one of medium length
we quickly add the energy input
and then we move to the bottom
where we will have to plan a way of automating that thing
since each items goes in a different slice
we use the smallest buses to push items up
to fill the items in
we use a dedicated ae2 network where we drop items inside an interface
and they get moved with storage buses to the machine
and if we do not want things to go into random places
we have to sort the storage buses priorities
we are not sorting the items with a filtering mechanism
because many recipes require the same items but in a different location layout
once we have fully configured the priorities
we add an interface connected to our main network
to automate the crafting requests
now we can slip inside a crafting pattern
and see if everything works as expected
once all the materials are prepared
they are correctly inserted into the slots
however once we tried to turn on the assembly line
we realize we have forgotten something
other than the crafting materials
the machine also need the instructions on how to build things
to get those
we have to do some research by scanning the lower tier of the thing we want to assemble
we quickly move to our EV scanner to do that
and we find out
it will take a quarter of hour to get the instructions for our assembly line
and we have to do that for every Luv component
anyways once our research is done
we can bring the data to the assembly line
which will finally start working
one motor is almost useless
so we shall start crafting more
but while it looked like everything was fine
one big issue was starting to build up
the items are being pushed to the assembly line
and since some buses were already filled
the overflow went to the wrong input slices
to avoid such thing
we have to add a blocking card to the assembly line network
and enable blocking mode on the interface with a pattern
and with that
we can see that the motors are being crafted one at a time
with everything being perfectly dosed
now we can scan the other components
and bring the data to the assembly line
however
there is only one space in the assembly line controller
but we can add a data access hatch
to increase that amount
the next issue is that
some components have too many ingredients
to fit our pattern terminal
of those
we manually craft just the bare minimum amount
to upgrade our pattern terminal to a fluid processing pattern terminal
this one has 32 input slots instead of nine
more than enough for any assembly line recipe
we quickly drop in the new patterns
and now we can move on to the next quest
which is probably going to be in the previous tier
to reach new planets with new materials
and that means crafting a new rocket
whose plates must now be assembled in an assembly line
we quickly set up the new crafting patterns
but then we run into a new issue
everything got stuck
because the plates did not split into the two buses
to fix that issue
we are going to use one simple solution
we prepare some molds that will rename the parts before sending them to the assembly line
to use it
we make a pattern that
with help of a press and the previously made mold
will rename the items
now we can edit the plate pattern
to use the two different items that won't merge
and with that
we can now start making complex assembly line recipes in an easy way
once everything is in the correct place
we can start crafting our rocket plates
which we use to make the tier 4 rocket
while that is being built
we can also prepare a new kind of miner
the ore drilling plant
that is the multi block version of the small miners
it has several buffs
but it requires to move a bigger structure
and need drilling fluid to work
and while that is crafting
we can get a better tool for locating minerals
an electric prospector
this thing can also be used to check the pollution in our base
but its main usage is to see the disposition of underground resources
and once we locate a good mining spot
we can build the ore drilling plant
which is going to mine all the minerals in a huge area
one chunk at a time layer by layer
and to avoid getting overwhelmed by its output
we can throttle it by decreasing the amount of drilling fluid we send
and now we are ready to start working on the LuV tier
but that's for the next episode
bye bye
欢迎回来！
今天我们要进入 LuV 级电压
想达成目标
当务之急便是一条装配线
这个多方块结构使用起来相当复杂
不过先让我们从结构方块开始
这些组件制作起来既不轻松又不便宜
甚至连 AE 自动下单都成了问题
主要问题是
我们的合成存储单元的空间出现了短缺
所以我们先做一些存储元件
同时也得来点并行单元
来加快制作过程
AE 的合成 CPU 升级过后
我们终于可以开始生产装配线所需的材料了
这需要一些时间
所以我们可以忙里偷闲做些其他事
比如刷些凋零
下界之星可是未来必需品
然而经过短暂的刷怪时间
我们发现
装配线的制作似乎没什么进展
主要问题是
并行单元发配材料的速度跟不上
各个机器的处理速度
我们可以增加并行单元
但最好的解决方案是减少 CPU 必须完成的任务量
我们可以将样板中的材料全部倍增
所以说
CPU 不会发配 64 次单个矿粉
而是一次性发配 64 个矿粉
正好在高炉旁边
我们顺便给它升级更好的线圈
有效提升它的并行
在倍增样板、重新下单后
我们可以看到各类原材料
被发配到机器的速度差异
没过多久
我们看到处理单元闲置了
原因是
我们正在一个小组装机中制作数千个贴片元件
一批做16个
每批也需要相当长的时间
我们已经将制作压力分配给不同的组装机
但效果并不明显
即使四个组装机应该比单个快四倍
但我们可以用更高级的组装机
但耗电会指数级增长
所以我们需要一个多方块组装机
第一个选项是 GT++ 的
但那需要我们目前无法制作的 ZPM 材料
第二种选择是在处理阵列中堆组装机
然而
在我们需要升级它的时候
它扩展性较差
第三种选择是使用我们上一集制作的
精密组装机的常规模式
问题是它的机械外壳
需要 LuV 组装机制作
然而
如果我们想让它在常规模式下工作
我们可以用不精密的电子机械方块
这样精密组装机将完全名副其实
准备好样板后
我们只准备能构成结构的最少材料
为了让那东西快速工作
我们将安装一个 16A 能源仓
由此
它比 16 联 IV 组装机快两倍
你们可以看到为这个电池组充电
已经对主电网产生巨大威胁
一切准备就绪后
我们安装好精密组装机
我们使用廉价的低级输入仓替代结构方块
现在我们开机
看到做几百个贴片电容轻而易举
最后一个瓶颈是电路组装机
所以我们再加几台机器
给每个电路制作步骤来一个
然后我们便可以小憩片刻，挂会机
或者说再去刷些下界之星
快速休息后
我们的装配线已经准备好了
这个多方块结构可以由不同长度构成
每额外片都将额外增加一个输入空间
我们也可以用扳手旋转它
垂直建造来节省空间
就目前而言
一个中等长度的就不赖
我们快速添加能源仓
然后移动到底部
开始准备自动化装配线
因为每个输入物都在不同的片层
我们将使用输入总线(ULV)
为了进行输入
我们把主网配方材料发配进子网
子网通过存储总线转移物品进机器
如果我们不想让物品随机排列
必须对存储总线的优先级进行排序
我们不会使用白名单来进行物品过滤
因为许多配方在不同的位置使用相同的物品
一旦我们配置好了优先级
便可以通过一个接口与我们主网相连
来完成自动化下单
现在可以往里面塞入一个样板
看看一切是否按预期进行
一旦所有的材料都准备好了
它们被正确放入输入总线中
然而，一旦我们试图开启装配线
我们发现忘记了什么
除了制作材料
机器还需要知道怎么去造
来完成这个目标
我们要研究其下级材料来获得研究结果
我们火速去 EV 扫描机做研究
我们发现
得到装配线的研究结果要一刻钟
而每个 LuV 组件都得经过这个过程
不管怎样，一旦我们的研究结束
我们把研究结果放进装配线
装配线终于开始工作了
一个马达没什么用处
我们要多做点
虽然一切看上去安然无恙
但一个大问题开始浮出水面
所有物品都被发配到装配线上
因为有些输入总线已经被填满
导致其溢出至错误的切片中
为了避免发生这样的事情
我们得给装配线网络加一个高级阻挡卡
并在接口中开启高级阻挡模式
有了这个
我们看到一次只会制作一个马达
物品的发配数量非常完美
现在我们可以扫描其他组件了
并将研究结果带到装配线
然而
装配线控制器中只有一个空槽
但我们可以添加一个数据访问舱口
来增加数据数量
下一个问题是
有些样板所写入的材料太多
当前的样板终端无法胜任
对那些物品
我们手动制作出最少的量
来升级至增广流体样板终端
它有 32 个写入栏，而非 9 个
对于任何装配线配方来说都绰绰有余
我们快速写好新样板
然后继续做下一个任务
任务在上一电压
去往具有新材料的新星球
这意味着制造一枚新火箭
而它的装甲板必须在装配线上制造
马上写好样板
但我们遇到了一个新问题
所有东西都卡住了
因为对应板没有均分进两片
为了解决这个问题
我们将使用一个简单的解决方案
用模具来重命名要送入装配线的物品
来使用它重命名材料
我们写了一个样板
在冲压机床和之前的模具的帮助下
材料将被重命名
现在我们可以重新编辑样板了
使用不会合并的两个物品
有了这个
我们以简单的方式制作复杂的装配线配方
一旦一切都在正确的地方
我们开始制作火箭板
我们将其用来制作 T4 火箭
在制造的同时
我们还可以准备一种新型矿机
采矿厂
它是小矿机的多方块版本
它有几点增强
但它需要一个更大的结构
并且需要钻井液才能工作
在制作的同时
我们找到更好定位矿物的工具
探矿仪
这东西也可以用来检查基地的污染情况
但它的主要用途是查看地下资源的配置
一旦我们找到一个好的矿脉点
我们建造采矿厂
来开采一大片区块的所有矿物
逐区块、逐层地运行
为避免被其输出物压垮
我们可以减少钻井液供应来控制它
现在我们可以推 LuV 的进度了
但那得是下一集的内容了
拜拜
（正式版已废弃）
（使用优先卡可以快速完成这工作）
（高级阻挡卡将物品检测拓展到它在的整个 ME 网络）